# Lewis Connolly







07889462020 lewis.connolly92@gmail.com Dundee, Scotland

Developer and experienced IT professional with a Master's in Computer Games Technology (Distinction) and an Honours degree in Computer Science. Over 10 years in IT Operations, specialising in automation across diverse technologies. Strong teamwork and communication skills, with a passion for continuous learning. Currently developing personal projects to gain further development experience. Seeking a full-time software development role.

### Education

Grade: Distinction

Sep 2023 - Sep 2024

MSc Computer Games Technology, Abertay University

Notable modules and grades:

• Programming for Games: A+

• Advanced Procedural Methods: A

• Game Design and Development: A

• Research Methods: A+

Master's Project: B+

Network Game Development: B

**Grade: 2:1** Sep 2008 – Sep 2012

BSc Hons Computer Science, Heriot-Watt University

Academic transcripts available on request.

#### Skills

C#, C++, Unity, Unreal, DirectX 11, DirectXTK, HLSL, ShaderLab, RenderDoc, Git, Visual Studio, SDL, SFML, Python, PowerShell, Blender, Applied Mathematics

### Projects

#### **Viva Las Mages (Student Game Development Project)**

Feb – Apr 2024

As the lead programmer and co-designer in a team of 7 (consisting of artists, designers and an audio specialist), developed a vertical slice of a game (playtime ~25 minutes) over 12 weeks based on a novel concept featuring dungeon exploration, card playing, and risk-reward mechanics.

#### Responsibilities included:

- All programming except audio.
- Gameplay and level design.
- UI design and implementation.
- Version control.

#### Master's Project (Procedural Cave Generation)

May – August 2024

As part of a dissertation, developed an application within Unity to procedurally generate 3D caves containing stalagmites and stalactites using cellular automata and isosurface algorithms.

#### Implemented features included:

- Multithreaded cellular automata algorithm.
- Marching Cubes 33 algorithm.
- Dual Contouring algorithm utilising a quadratic error function and singular value decomposition.
- Stalagmite and stalactite generation.
- Tessellation and Phong smoothing.
- Perlin noise-based vertex displacement.
- Texture blending based on surface angle.



### Employment History

#### IT Infrastructure Engineer

Sep 2017 - Present

**Zonal Retail Data Systems** (Hospitality Technology Solutions Provider)

- Responsible for helping to increase the performance and resilience of an extensive infrastructure platform, with a focus on automation, virtualisation, storage and backup solutions.
- Developed PowerShell scripting solutions to automate processes (such as configuring servers and virtual machines), monitor critical infrastructure, and solve problems in an efficient and repeatable manner.
- Produced documentation and delivered presentations to explain and demonstrate concepts and solutions to fellow engineers and management.

### Multiple IT infrastructure roles

Nov 2013 – Mar 2017

## Hewlett-Packard/Hewlett Packard Enterprise/DXC Technology

(IT Services and Consulting)

- Joined graduate programme and held positions of *Peripherals Integration* Engineer, Build Integration Engineer, and Build Engineer which became a permanent, non-graduate role.
- Installed and maintained hardware and software in non-production data centre environments used as development, integration and testing platforms.
- In collaboration with a colleague, hosted presentations and site tours for work experience students on a regular basis.

#### " References

Available on request.